(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-07T21:56:26.498546",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I'm always causing you trouble, but...
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I'm always bothering you endlessly, but...
それでも隣にいてくれる君のそばにずっと
Even so, I want to be by your side forever, as you stay by mine.
曖昧な言葉じゃ真面目な君には伝わらない
Vague words won't get through to someone as serious as you,
頑丈なそのハートを覗いてみたい 溶かしてみたい
I want to peek into that sturdy heart of yours, I want to melt it down.
そんなとき こんな魔法はどうかな？
At times like that, how about a spell like this?
やっちゃえ！ せーの！
Let's do it! Ready, set, go!
あやふやだっていいの！
Even if it's uncertain, it's fine!
Which one to be, Watch me, do magic! 妄想以上の展開 もう止められないの
Which one to be, Watch me, do magic! An unfolding beyond imagination, I can't stop it!
横面の賽 溢れる思いで空回り
Rolling the dice, running in circles with overwhelming feelings,
振り撒ける Happy なイメージ 手振り回す Fancy なマジック
Scattering a happy image, waving around fancy magic,
また君にくどくど言われちゃうけど ほらこんな Day by day
You'll probably nag me again, but look, in a Day by day like this,
恋
Love,
あの日から Falling in love with you
Ever since that day, I'm falling in love with you,
変わらないから ずっと Only you
It won't change, so forever it's only you.
だからほらうだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying,
つかめ ハッピーエンディング
Grab hold of that happy ending!
いつまでも隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep laughing by your side forever!
いつも仲間外れで ひとりぼっちの毎日
Always left out, living lonely days all alone,
そんな私の前に現れた君は 同じ寂しさを抱えている
When you appeared before me, carrying that same loneliness...
とても優しい人
A truly kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
Even now there are many things to worry about, but...
もう私も君もひとりじゃない
Neither I nor you are alone anymore.
愛おしくて 愛おしい この日々が ずっと 続きますように
I hope these precious, dear days will continue forever.
飛ばせ HappyなImage
Send out a happy image!
とびっきりの FancyなMagic
An extraordinary, fancy magic!
また君に くどくど言われそうだけれど
It feels like you'll lecture me again, but...
そんなの Take Fight Take 愛？
Is that Take Fight, Take Love?
あの日から Falling in love with you
Ever since that day, falling in love with you.
気づいてほしいの Love with you
I want you to notice, love with you.
だからこそ うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
That's why this is no time to be idling around.
次はどんな Planning
What's the next planning?
そしてまた今日も Happening
And today there's another happening!
明日はどんな おかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what strange things will happen tomorrow.
ずっと隣で見ててね
Keep watching by my side forever, okay?
HappyなImage
Happy image!
FancyなMagic
Fancy magic!
HappyなImage
Happy image!
FancyなMagic
Fancy magic!
みんなー！
Everyone~!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live stream today!
改めてまして、もぐもぐおかゆ〜！
Once again, Mogumogu Okayu~!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
本日はこちら、ハッシュタグ「猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026」でいっぱい呟いてください！
Please tweet a lot today using the hashtag #NekomataOkayuBirthday2026!
配信終わったらね、すぐ見に行っちゃうんだからね！ふふふっ
Once the stream ends, I'll go check them right away! Hehehe.
そして、みんな見てー！
And everyone, look!
今回のライブは「みあーどくっきー」というタイトルを付けましたー！
I titled this live performance 'Miado Cookie'!
「みあーど」っていうのは、「君を」っていう意味があるんだけど
'Miado' means 'you', but...
なんで「みあーど」って付けたのかなとか考えながらライブを見てくれると嬉しいなーと思っていますよ！
I'd be happy if you watched while thinking about why I named it 'Miado'!
そして...
And...
見てー！このステージ！とっても可愛いでしょ？
Look at this stage! Isn't it super cute?
でも、可愛いだけじゃないんだよー！
But it's not just cute!
すごいね、曲によってガラッと雰囲気変わるように作っていただいたので、そこもね、注目してみてくだい！
It's amazing, it was made so the atmosphere changes completely with each song, so please keep an eye on that too!
「えっ？」ってなるかもしんないね！
You might go, 'Huh?!'
そして、ギフトも今回盛りだくさんでございますー！
And we have plenty of gifts this time as well!
ワクワクドキドキ...いや僕もね、今から、なんかちゃんと振付とか歌とか行けんのかなと思いつつ...
So excited and nervous... well, even I'm wondering if I can pull off all the dance moves and singing...
ではね、みんなと楽しく自分のお誕生日をお祝いできたらなと思っておりますー！
Anyway, I hope we can celebrate my birthday together while having lots of fun!
そして最後に、最後にみんなに喜んでもらえるような告知用意してあるので、ぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえればなと思っております！
And finally, I've prepared an announcement at the end that you'll all love, so please enjoy until the very end!
次の曲行ってみよっか！
Shall we move on to the next song?
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君がひとり『xx』してるの知ってるの
Hey, I know. I know you're doing 'xx' all by yourself.
ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Trembling and twitching, your voice is leaking out completely.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
Just be honest and say it. It's totally obvious, so spill it.
効いてんの？
Is it working on you?
普通 普通 恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ
Normal, normal, is it embarrassing? Everyone's just hiding it.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears all alone.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音 ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, whining alone at karaoke in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって
We're together until morning comes, even if you cry more.
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you no matter how many times it takes.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, okay?
お願い 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて シェイク シェイク 愛の才能で
Please, I want you. Let me comfort you, shake shake with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたいの
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away. I want to stay soaked.
ねえ いいでしょう？ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, isn't it fine? I'm telling you I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
お願い 君が欲しいの 頼り散らして シックラブなんて最高ね
Please, I want you. Rely on me completely, sick love is the absolute best.
分けてくれなきゃ 君の「痛い」感じてたい
If you don't share it with me, I want to feel your 'pain'.
ねえ いいでしょう？ 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, isn't it fine? I'm telling you I want to suck it up and save you.
見たいの見たいの見たいの見たい 見たいの見たいの見たいの見たい 君の中
I want to see, I want to see, inside of you, I want to see...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり悔しがってんの
Hey, I know... you're frustrated all by yourself.
知ってるよ ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん 君を推すことをやめない
I know... my heart's pounding, right? I won't stop supporting you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君はできる子知ってるよ 辛い時は
Hey, I know... I know you can do it. When times are tough,
弱いくらいでちょうどいい あたしそれても好きだよ
showing weakness is just right. I still love you regardless.
MWAH! お願い君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
MWAH! Please, I want you. Call my name.
いつだって愛に参上 君はひとりだ
Arriving with love anytime. You feel all alone,
だから歌う ひとりじゃない もういいでしょう
so I sing—you're not alone. Isn't that enough now?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだ たたたってば
Solo play is over now, I'm telling you!
君が病めるときも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you're sick, I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'm always watching over you.
そうよ 怖くないのよ
That's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
MWAH! お願い君が欲しいの 慰めさせて Shake Shake
MWAH! Please, I want you. Let me comfort you, Shake Shake.
愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ
With the talent of love, if you don't cry for me,
枯れてしまう 濡れていたい ねぇいいでしょう
I'll wither away. I want to stay soaked, hey, isn't that okay?
涙取って飲み干したいんだ たたたってば
I want to take your tears and drink them up, I'm telling you!
MWAH! お願い君が欲しいの 頼り散らかして Seek Now
MWAH! Please, I want you. Lean on me all you want, Seek Now.
なんて最高ね 分けてくれなきゃ
How wonderful! If you don't share with me,
君の痛い 感じてたい 慰めてたい
I want to feel your pain and comfort you.
吸い取って救いたいんだ たたたってば
I want to suck it all up and save you, I'm telling you!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙出してるの
Hey, I know... you're shedding tears all by yourself.
知ってるよ グスングスンへこんでさ 弱音吐いたらいいんじゃない
I know... sniffling and feeling down, why not let out your weakness?
朝が来るまでいっそこーもっと泣いたって
Why not just cry even more like this until morning comes?
何度だって受け止めてあげる もう我慢しないで出して
I'll embrace you as many times as it takes, don't hold back anymore, let it out.
ててててば
I'm telling you!
ながら優等生 今宵も自分と密会です
A casual honor student, having a secret rendezvous with myself tonight too.
しんどいわ しんどいわ あーつらつら合掌
It's exhausting, it's exhausting, ah, praying with hands joined.
ほんとは劣等生 あたしはあたしに説教です
Actually an underachiever, lecturing myself.
しんどいわ しんどいわ もーいやいや絶交
It's exhausting, it's exhausting, no way, cutting ties.
心配無用 心配無用 これは笑えるジョークソング
No need to worry, no need to worry, this is a laughable joke song.
新米も老害も みんな歌えるポップソング
Both rookies and old folks can all sing this pop song.
まあまあそれ噂っすよ ただの紙切れっすよ
Well, well, that's just a rumor, it's just a piece of paper.
いいから 早く ハンコ押せや
Enough already, hurry up and stamp the seal!
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそう言ってるもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! That's what a devil would say!
あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいジャン
Ah, I died, I died! Don't you want to love me?
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even so, if you get hooked, even so, if you fall in love,
あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェル エンジェル
Ah, I died, I died! Angel, angel!
わー！ 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】
Wow! [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News]
わー！ 汚いね わー！ 飛べないね
Wow! So dirty. Wow! Can't fly, huh?
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Ah, I died, I died!
本物の天使 スルーして ご臨終
Ignoring a real angel, off to your demise!
あくまで天使ジャン？ 最強ジャン？
After all, you're an angel, right? The strongest, right?
「君のため」って名言の悪意
The malice behind the famous phrase "for your sake."
「夢は叶う」で奪ったサラリー
The salary stolen with "dreams come true."
はあ 中毒性の高いもんには罠があるんだな
Sigh, highly addictive things always have a trap.
魂抜かれちゃって やあねえ やあねえ
Having your soul pulled out, how dreadful, how dreadful.
光り輝く輪っかで この首が締まっていく
This neck gets strangled by a shining halo.
嘘をつくほど緩んでいく 言えない SOS
The more I lie, the looser it gets—an unspeakable SOS.
白いペンキかぶりましょう なりきってしまいましょう
Let's pour white paint over ourselves, let me play the part completely.
嘘をつくほど楽になる ほらやってちゃって
The more I lie, the easier it gets—come on, just do it.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった ああ
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Ah, I died, I died, ah!
それでもウガっちゃうけど それでも嫌っちゃうけど
Even so, I get cynical, even so, I hate it,
なりきって 笑顔で エンジェル エンジェル
Playing the role with a smile, angel, angel!
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそう言ってるもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! That's what a devil would say!
あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいジャン
Ah, I died, I died! Don't you want to love me?
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even so, if you get hooked, even so, if you fall in love,
あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェル エンジェル
Ah, I died, I died! Angel, angel!
わー！ 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】
Wow! [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News]
わー！ 汚いね わー！ 飛べないね
Wow! So dirty. Wow! Can't fly, huh?
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Ah, I died, I died!
本物の天使 スルーして ご臨終
Ignoring a real angel, off to your demise!
わー！ 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】 【悲報】
Wow! [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News] [Sad News]
わー！ 醜いね わー！ 映えないね
Wow! So hideous. Wow! Doesn't look good at all.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Ah, I died, I died!
本物の悪魔になっても ブレス・ユー
Even if you become a real devil, bless you.
あくまで天使ジャン？ 最強ジャン？
After all, you're an angel, right? The strongest, right?
充電器を貸して！ またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
Lend me a charger! Once again, because of you, I'm worn out.
終電見逃して またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
Missed the last train, once again, because of me, I couldn't go home.
繋がっていようね
Let's stay connected, okay?
Let's stay connected,
消耗戦に持ち込んで
dragging each other into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張りあった
We dragged each other down.
沈殿した思い出で
With our settled memories,
ずーっといっしょ
together forever.
参観日になったって
Even on open school day,
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like no one was looking at me.
散々死に掛かって
Having come close to death so many times,
昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I tried not to expect anything from the daytime city.
そうやって守った孤独さえ
Even the solitude I protected like that
めちゃくちゃになった
became a complete mess.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I've always wanted to die so badly,
こんな顔大事にしたいと思えないの
I can't bring myself to cherish a face like this.
共に過ごした日々の
The days we spent together,
ささやかな幸せが
the modest happiness—
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope it becomes an irreplaceable trauma.
離れ離れなんて
Being separated and all
誰かが吐かせたバグだよね
is just a bug someone spat out, right?
あなたの一生の後悔
As the regret of your whole life,
として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you till the end.
大切なものってなに？
What is precious to you?
A. 今無くしたそれ
A. That which you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも 病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中で ずーっといっしょ
through our gruesome history, together forever.
もうちょっと普通に
Wish I could have felt sad more normally
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
about sad things.
長調のチューンに
Leaving my feelings to major key tunes,
感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to make it easier for myself.
せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね
Do live your life as best as you can.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I've always wanted to die so badly,
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of a song like that.
あなただけ一人で
Don't you dare think that you alone
あたしの目を盗んで 幸せになろうなんて思わないで
can be happy behind my back.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
Ever since that night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I have been broken.
あなたの一生の後悔
As the regret of your whole life,
として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you till the end.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that got stuck and won't come off,
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている
it keeps flashing back over and over again.
最悪でないよ
It's not the worst.
一緒に居た時の方があたし可愛かったなあ
I was way cuter when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔
As the regret of your whole life,
として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you till the end.
Q. 大切なものってなに？
Q. What is precious to you?
A. 今無くしたそれ
A. That which you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも 病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと眠っていても
even if you sleep with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢でずーっといっしょ
we'll be together forever in matching nightmares.
愛♡スクリーム！
Love Scream!
G-I-V-E M-E
愛♡スクリーム！
Love Scream!
G-I-V-E M-E
教えて！もっと あなたの事
Tell me! Tell me more about you!
Tell me more, more, more! Tell me more, more, more!
聞かせて！もっと あなたの声
Let me hear it! Let me hear more of your voice!
Let me hear more, more, more! Let me hear more, more, more!
こんなドキドキもう抑えきれない
I can no longer hold back this pounding heart!
Oh I need you, Oh I need you
友達は卒業
Graduating from being friends,
運命の私
I am your destiny!
見つけてほしいの
I want you to find me!
勇気を出して
Summon up your courage!
見つめる作戦
My "stare right at you" strategy!
目が合えば FOR YOU!
When our eyes meet, FOR YOU!
止められない
Unstoppable,
YEAH YEAH YEAH この恋 この愛で メルメルティ 溶けちゃうよ
Yeah, yeah, yeah! With this love, this affection, I'm melting away!
ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？気づいて MY DARLING
Hey, hey, hey! Notice me, my darling!
届け！大好き！
Reach them! I love you!
愛♡スクリーム！スクリーム！叫びましょう！
Love Scream! Scream! Let's scream it out!
スクリーム！アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice Cream!
愛♡スクリーム！スクリーム！叫びましょう！
Love Scream! Scream! Let's scream it out!
スクリーム！アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice Cream!
ルーナちゃん！
Luna-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミントよりもあなた♡
More than chocolate mint, I like you!
わためちゃん！
Watame-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりもあなた♡
More than strawberry flavor, I like you!
おかゆちゃん！
Okayu-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあなた♡
More than cookies & cream, I like you!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好き アイスクリーム！
Of course, we love ice cream!
止められない
Unstoppable,
YEAH YEAH YEAH この恋 この愛で メルメルティ 溶けちゃうよ
Yeah, yeah, yeah! With this love, this affection, I'm melting away!
ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？気づいて MY DARLING
Hey, hey, hey! Notice me, my darling!
届け！大好き！
Reach them! I love you!
愛♡スクリーム！スクリーム！叫びましょう！
Love Scream! Scream! Let's scream it out!
スクリーム！アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice Cream!
叫びましょう
Let's scream!
スクリーム
Scream!
アイスクリーム
Ice Cream!
お願い見つけて マイダーリン
Please find me, my darling!
お願い気づいて マイダーリン
Please notice me, my darling!
勇気を出して
Plucking up my courage...
近づく作戦
The approach strategy...
手と手が触れて
Our hands touch each other...
止められない
I can't stop it!
イェイイェイイェイ この恋 この愛で メルメルティ 溶けちゃうよ
Yeah, yeah, yeah! With this love, with this affection, mel-melting, I'm melting away!
ねぇねぇねぇ 気づいて マイダーリン
Hey, hey, hey! Notice me, my darling!
それは あなた
That person is... you!
愛! 愛! スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love! Love! Scream, scream, let's scream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
愛! 愛! スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love! Love! Scream, scream, let's scream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
愛! 愛! スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love! Love! Scream, scream, let's scream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
愛! 愛! スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love! Love! Scream, scream, let's scream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
ラブラブラブラブ...
Love, love, love...
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな ファンタジックな物語が
A magical, dreamlike, fantastical story...
世界に感染 不快に蔓延
...infects the world, unpleasantly spreading!
待って そんなの聞いてないってば
Wait, I never heard about anything like this!
根本的に 痛い異常行動
Fundamentally painful abnormal behavior...
支える 稼げない妄想量
...backed up by an unearnable amount of delusion.
本能的に 深い破壊衝動
Instinctively deep destructive impulses...
照らす 確かじゃない象度
...illuminating an uncertain hatred.
恋の導火線
The fuse of love,
いざ 火を灯し
now light the fire!
ひとつ ここらで本調子
Let's get in full gear right here!
脳細胞に
Into the brain cells,
今
right now,
叩き込め
hammer it in!
わからないことだらけを
All these things I don't understand,
あざとい きわどい 笑わないで
calculated, risky, don't laugh at me!
いつも いつも ごまかしてばっかりね
You're always, always just making excuses!
いらない 知らない おだてないで
Don't need it, don't know, don't flatter me!
言えない 消えない 思い込め
Unspoken, unfading, fill it with thoughts:
愛の強制ミューティレーション
Love's forced mutilation!
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな ファンタジックな物語が
A magical, dreamlike, fantastical story...
世界に感染 不快に蔓延
...infects the world, unpleasantly spreading!
待って こんなの聞いてないって ダーリン
Wait, I never heard about anything like this, darling!
ベターな恋愛 エラーな展開
Standard romance, error-ridden development,
だって それじゃあつまらないでしょ
because otherwise it would be boring, right?
切り抜けて
Break through it,
引き付けて
attract them,
愛の顔面ストレート
Love's straight punch to the face!
根本的に まずい異常行動
Fundamentally bad abnormal behavior...
支える イカれた情報量
...backed up by a crazy amount of information.
圧倒的に 淡い母性本能
An overwhelmingly faint maternal instinct...
暴く 飢えた奴隷根性
...exposing a starved slave mentality.
愛の導火線 いざ火をつけて
The fuse of love, now light the fire!
頭の中はアルデンテ
Inside my head is al dente!
生細胞に
Into raw cells,
今 流し込め
pour it in now!
耐えがたいことだらけを
All these unbearable things,
冷たい ふれあい 遊ばないで
a cold touch, don't play around with me!
いつも いつも 当てつけつけるばっかりね
You're always, always making spiteful remarks!
つたない うかがい ふざけないで
Clumsy probing, don't fool around!
言えない 消えない 思い込め
Unspoken, unfading, fill it with thoughts:
愛の眼球アイスピック
Love's eyeball ice pick!
好きな人の 好きな人ってだけで嫌い
Disliking someone just because they're liked by the one I like...
都合の良い子演じて一生 終わりたくないんだよ
...I don't want to spend my whole life acting like a convenient girl!
狂った未来に迎合 終わった抵抗
Catering to a crazy future, resistance over...
いっそこのまま目を塞いで
...better to just close your eyes like this!
切って爽快 くらって崩壊
Slashing feels refreshing, getting hit causes collapse!
知って後悔 望んだ将来
Knowing brings regret, the desired future...
手を繋いで 場を繋いで
...holding hands, keeping the mood!
ファンタジックなすったもんだが
A fantastical messy affair...
頭に感染 危険に発展
...infecting the brain, developing into danger!
聞いてないって ダーリン
I didn't hear about this, darling!
ベターな恋愛
A cliché romance,
エラーな展開
an error-filled plot,
だってそれじゃ つまらないでしょ
'Cause that'd be boring, wouldn't it?
踏みつけて 焼き付けて
Trample it down, burn it in,
溶けそうな 酸素神経
sensory nerves about to melt,
壊れそうな 群狂本能
crowd-crazy instinct about to break,
崩れそうな 情を前に
in front of emotions about to collapse,
愛の脳内レボリューション！
a brain-bound revolution of love!
ドキドキメキ気流に 私は乗っている きっとね
I'm riding on this heart-pounding flow, surely.
なんか言葉にできないこと
Things I somehow can't put into words,
ちょっと心の雑音騒がすこと
things that stir up a little noise in my heart,
なんとなく今日を照らすこと
things that somehow illuminate today,
ちょっと好みの花見つけた！
I found a flower I kind of like!
白い霧ばかりエブリデイ 探したいものさえ探せないよ
Everyday is full of white fog, I can't even search for what I want to find.
わくわくした sofa ダイアリー 知らんぷりして放り出すなんて
An exciting sofa diary, pretending not to notice and tossing it aside...
ライヤイヤイヤ...
Liar, liar, liar, liar...
やるせなかったハート
My helpless heart.
でも だけど
"But, however..."
きっと 可能性あり
"Surely, there's a possibility."
気持ちいい風に浮遊して
Floating in the pleasant breeze,
うんとすっとちょっともっといつかは飛べたらいいな！
I hope I can fly someday, much more and much smoother!
ドキドキメキ気流に私は乗っている きっとね
I'm riding on this heart-pounding flow, surely.
分からないストーリーにビビらないで
Don't be scared of a story you don't understand.
キラキラ空想に世界が踊る 笑って
The world dances in sparkling fantasies, laugh along!
縮こまってる時間はないな
There's no time to shrink back!
私を知りたい！ 何もかもがまだ分からない ない ない ない
I want to know myself! I still don't know anything at all!
私を見つけたい！
I want to find myself!
「行ってきます」を声にできたなら
If I can say "I'm off" out loud,
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
ちゃっちゃかちゃっちゃか深呼吸 優しくあるたびに失速
Taking quick deep breaths, slowing down every time I try to be kind,
つまんない筆跡は夢がない ちょっと嫌いな自分見つけた
boring handwriting lacks dreams, I found a part of myself I kinda dislike.
黒い霧覆うエブリデイ
Everyday covered in black fog,
雨に打たれて帰りたくなるの
getting hit by rain makes me want to go home.
わくわくしたそんなダイアリー 少し浮かれて走り出すなんて
Such an exciting diary, running off getting a bit carried away...
まぁいいや いいや いいや いいや
Oh well, whatever, whatever, whatever.
シャカリキで行くハート
A heart going full speed ahead!
お気に入りのアクセは無くしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory.
まだ何も分かっちゃいないんだ
I still don't understand anything yet.
「好き」って気持ちに向かいたい
I want to head toward the feeling of "love."
あの星のように輝きたい
I want to shine like that star!
ドキドキメキ気流に私は酔っている やっぱね
I'm drunk on this heart-pounding flow, after all.
答えのない世界で生きてるせいです
It's because I'm living in a world with no answers.
未来は優秀にあっても変わらないし 叫んで
Even if the future is bright, nothing changes, so shout it out!
私らしく体現！
Embody it in my own way!
ドキドキメキ気流を乗り越えた先には
Beyond overcoming this heart-pounding flow,
分からないストーリーが待っている
an unknown story is waiting.
小さな勇気で何かを変えよう
Let's change something with a little bit of courage!
あーね 大切な話があるんだ
Ah right, there's something important I need to tell you.
此処にない探し物があるんだ
There's something I'm looking for that isn't here.
だから旅に出ます
So I'm setting off on a journey.
そのうち帰ります
I'll be back eventually.
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
夜が明ける
Night turns into day,
朝目覚める
I wake up in the morning,
首痛める
my neck hurts,
この身体に自分がいる
I am inside this body.
君と喋る
I talk with you,
飯を食べる
I eat a meal,
服を着てる
I wear clothes,
そのすべてが不気味である
all of that feels eerie.
変だ 変だ 変だ 変だ
It's strange, strange, strange, strange.
駅の改札通り抜ける
Passing through the station ticket gate,
こんな平和 平和 平和 平和
such peace, peace, peace, peace,
当たり前でウケる
taking it for granted is hilarious.
犬の名前は
The dog's name is
なんとなくポチだ
somehow Pochi.
世界は 世界は なんとなく終わりそうで
The world, the world seems like it's going to end somehow,
存在を抱えたまま夕焼けに溶けていくよ
and carrying our existence, we dissolve into the sunset.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
There's no point in living, no point in trying—none, none, none, it might be useless.
千年後何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
A thousand years from now nothing will remain, but I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all utterly meaningless.
月が昇る 星が光る 虫が跳ねる それを見てる
The moon rises, stars shine, insects hop, and we watch them.
あれ いつからここにいるんだっけ
Huh, since when have we been here?
いつまでここにいられるんだっけ
How much longer can we stay here?
何もかもなれないままで 化け物から逃れてるだけ
Unable to become anything at all, just running away from monsters.
座敷牢でイメージを浮かべて ストップした思考は敵だらけ
Conjuring images in a confinement room, stalled thoughts are full of enemies.
太郎の名前は 今でも太郎で
Taro's name is still Taro today,
次郎の名前は 今では花子だ
while Jiro's name is Hanako now.
時間 は 時間は なんとなく通り過ぎて
Time, time passes by somehow,
ゴミ溜めで埋もれたまま星空を眺めてるよ
and buried in a heap of trash, we gaze at the starry sky.
愛する意味も 恋する意味も ないないない 嘘かもしれない
There's no meaning in loving, no meaning in falling in love—none, none, none, it might all be a lie.
1＋1もよく分からんけど それでも君を守っていたい
I don't even get 1 + 1 very well, but I still want to protect you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all utterly meaningless.
それでもぼくらはトンネルで息を止める
Even so, we hold our breath in tunnels,
鳥居が視れて鶴を折る
spot a torii gate and fold paper cranes,
肉球を触る 横断歩道の白い部分だけを踏む
touch paw pads, and step only on the white stripes of crosswalks.
それでもぼくらは間違った事をする
Even so, we keep making mistakes,
正しいと思い込む
convincing ourselves that we're right.
頭いいから分かっていた
Because I was smart, I understood,
また分かった気になっていたんだ
or rather, I just convinced myself I did once again.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も
Meaning to live, meaning to try—
ないないない ないないない ないないない
None, none, none, none, none, none, none...
それでもやるしかない
Even so, we just have to keep going!
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
There's no point in living, no point in trying—none, none, none, it might be useless.
千年後何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
A thousand years from now nothing will remain, but I still want to laugh with you.
夢を叶えても 悟り開いても 結局は孤独かもしれない
Even if dreams come true, even if enlightenment is reached, in the end it might still be lonely.
おばけになっても 虚無に帰しても それでも君と笑っていたいな
Even if we become ghosts or return to nothingness, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all utterly meaningless.
そうぼくらはみんな意味不明 だから
Yes, we are all utterly meaningless, so...
そう簡単な祈りだった 端から
Yes, it was a simple prayer right from the start,
段々と消える感嘆
an exclamation gradually fading away.
今から緞帳が上がるから
From now, the stage curtain is going up,
静かな会場を後にさよなら
so goodbye to the quiet venue as we leave it behind.
言いかけていた事が一つ消えてまた増えて 背中後ろめたさが残る
A thing I was about to say vanishes, then another grows, leaving guilt behind my back.
従いたい心根を吐き出さぬように込めて 胸の中が檻のように濁る
Suppressing my obedient nature so it won't spill out, my chest grows murky like a cage.
受け止めたいことが自分さえ抱えられず持て余したそれを守っている
Unable to handle what I want to accept myself, I protect the overflow.
霞んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす 何を言うべきかわからなくて
A hazy voice burns my dry throat completely, not knowing what I ought to say.
感じてたものが遠く放たれていた
What I felt was cast far away,
同じようで違うなんだか違う
seemingly the same, yet somehow different.
いつまで行こうか どこまで行けるのか
How long shall we go, how far can we reach?
定かじゃないなら何を想うの
If it's uncertain, what do you think?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら
If we part ways, if we lose our path,
その度に何回も繋がれるように
so that we can reconnect as many times as it takes,
ここに居てくれるなら 離さずいられたら
if you stay here with me, if I can hold on to you,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
we'll be saved by a sensation no one knows yet.
平穏とは消耗を以て代わりに成す
Tranquility is achieved in exchange for exhaustion;
実際はどう代わりはなく
in reality, there's no substitute.
享楽とは嘘で成る
Pleasure is made of lies.
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was a simple prayer,
端から段々と消える感嘆
An admiration fading gradually from the edge.
今から帳が上がるから
The curtain is about to rise,
静かな会場を後にサヨナラ
So say goodbye to the quiet venue.
言いかけていたことが一つ消えてまた増えて
One thing I was about to say vanished, then grew again,
背中に後ろめたさが残る
Leaving a feeling of guilt behind my back.
従いたい心根を
Holding back my true feelings
吐き出さぬように込めて
So as not to spit them out,
胸の中が淀のように濁る
My chest grows murky like stagnant water.
受け止めたいことが
The things I want to accept,
自分さえ抱えられず
I can't even hold myself,
持て余したそれを守っている
Protecting what I cannot handle.
霞んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
A hazy voice parches my throat, burning and filling it,
何を言うべきかわからなくて
Not knowing what I should say,
感じてたものが遠く放たれていた
What I felt was cast far away.
同じようで違う 何だか違う
Seemingly same yet different, somehow different.
君と泣く
Crying with you,
君と笑う
Laughing with you,
君と怒る
Getting angry with you,
君と歌う
Singing with you,
君と踊る
Dancing with you,
君と話す
Talking with you,
いつまで続くだろうと
How long will this last, I wonder,
同じように同じように呟く
Muttering over and over again,
今は忘れないよう 刻まれた空気の
So I don't forget now, this engraved atmosphere,
これから何度思い出すのだろう
How many times will I remember this from now on?
僕らだけが
If only we...
僕らが離れるなら
If we are separated,
僕らが迷うなら
If we lose our way,
その度に何回も繋がれるように
So that we can connect time and again,
ここに居てくれるなら
If you stay here for me,
離さずいれたら
If I could hold on without letting go,
まだ誰も知らない
With a sensation no one knows yet,
感覚で僕の
Everything I live for,
生きているすべてを確かめて正しくして
Verify and make it right.
Expected to be
Very expected to be
(アンハッピー？) 悩める人の子よ
(UNHAPPY?) O child of man in distress,
(アンラッキー？) 人ならざる者も
(UNLUCKY?) O non-human beings as well,
(ビーハッピー！) 撓まず目指せよ
(BE HAPPY!) Aim forward unyielding,
(アンデッド) 生きているんだし
(UNDEAD) After all, you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you averted your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
And the dull future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
Are in counseling, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace.
(アンハッピー？)
(UNHAPPY?)
(アンラッキー？)
(UNLUCKY?)
(ビーハッピー！)
(BE HAPPY!)
(アンデッド)
(UNDEAD)
ねえねえ ねえねえ 何だか どうして 戦っているような そんな気がするの
Hey, hey, somehow, why do I feel like I'm fighting?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch, don't even want to touch,
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分 と
My past self, self, self, self, and...
どうも とっくに死んでる
A showdown with a transparent ghost
透明な亡霊と対決
Who died long ago,
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
In the depths of innocent, painful memories.
残念 もう居ないのに
Too bad, even though it's gone now,
あれ？ そっちが良い？
Huh? You like that better?
アイロニーね
How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my present self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label,
YES! 要はコンプレックス
YES! In short, a complex,
取り憑かれているみたい
Like being possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ 離れない
Coiled around, still unable to part,
在りし日の自分
My self from days gone by.
(UNDEAD) 死んじゃいない
(UNDEAD) Not dead yet,
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and your past,
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive means to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't content yourself with remaining unhappy,
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not even trying to be happy.
この世 この世は
This world, this world is
奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
A strange, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って 遭って やっと 始まる 物語
A story that finally begins upon meeting and encountering,
さあ 人か 化物か
Now, human or monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
Moving on, peace, peace.
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
カットイン 何だか どうして 未来になんぞ 何の希望もない 期待できないような気がして
Cut-in! Somehow, why do I feel like there's no hope or expectation for the future?
もう十分生きてる
I've already lived long enough,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Sick of clichés and déjà vu,
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Too bad, a consequence of accumulated experience,
形骸化された神話と 退屈な進化
Hollowed-out myths and boring evolution.
要は 刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want excitement,
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Got bored, got used to it.
なんて 整っていくガイダンス
And so, guidance falling into place,
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
It feels like being covered up.
吸い尽くして
Draining it all dry,
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
That, this, any of it tastes the same.
(UNDEAD) 死んじゃいない
(UNDEAD) Not dead yet,
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and your past,
何時の世も 過去も 未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future both exist in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果せよ
Fulfill your existence with honest perseverance,
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending.
(UNDEAD) 死んじゃいない
(UNDEAD) Not dead yet,
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you,
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is no different from being dead, a corpse of an undead.
(アンハッピー？) 悩める人の子よ
(UNHAPPY?) O child of man in distress,
(アンラッキー？) 人ならざる者も
(UNLUCKY?) O non-human beings as well,
(ビーハッピー！) 撓まず目指せよ
(BE HAPPY!) Aim forward unyielding,
(アンデッド) 生きているんだし
(UNDEAD) After all, you are alive.
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Wallowing in misery or finding happiness,
そう 全部 全部 お前だ
That's right, it's all up to you.
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
All times and places, everything, all creation, peace, peace.
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
人の在る 所に いつも 憂い事
Wherever humans exist, there are always anxieties,
生き抜け この 化物 ばかりの 物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った
"Emotions are completely useless anyway," the devil said.
「何もかも捨てちまえよ」
"Throw everything away."
嗚呼 快不快も 喜怒哀楽さえも
Ah, comfort and discomfort, even all emotions!
どうしようもない事実 ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
A helpless truth: humans cannot escape the end.
「誰も抗えない欲望に従え」
"Submit to desires that no one can resist."
思考を休めるな 脳みそを回せ
Don't stop thinking, keep your brain working.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is looking at you anyway."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる？
Why do you feel ashamed of losing your mind?
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you all the perfectly wrong way to dance,
いっせーので捨てちまえ そんな命ならば
so on three, throw it away if that's all your life is.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, tens of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ 空っぽの頭蓋骨だろ
No matter what, it's just an empty skull, right?
わかっているのかい
Do you understand?
感情なんていつ何時でも邪魔だって悪魔は言った
"Emotions are always in the way," the devil said.
「反論の余地などない」
"There's no room for argument."
嗚呼 人生に意味を与えておくれ
Ah, please give meaning to life!
420でさえも救えない終焉があると知った
I learned there's an end that even 420 cannot save.
「誰も疑わない神様を疑え」
"Doubt the God that no one doubts."
思考を休めるな 脳みそを回せ
Don't stop thinking, keep your brain working.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is looking at you anyway."
躊躇っている数秒の無益さを知れ
Realize the futility of the few seconds you hesitate.
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you all the perfectly wrong way to dance,
いっせーので捨てちまえ そんな命ならば
so on three, throw it away if that's all your life is.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, tens of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ 頭ん中空っぽなこと
No matter what, that your head is empty—
わかっていないようだ
you don't seem to realize.
承認欲にレイプされ 死んだ花をぶら下げている女
A woman raped by desire for recognition, dangling a dead flower.
何かを愛することすらままならないまま餌を待つだけ
Unable to even love anything, just waiting for bait.
踊り方を知らない 芸術の価値などわからない奴らに
For those who don't know how to dance and don't get the value of art,
堕落していれば何も見えないまま
as long as you fall, you remain blind to everything.
真善美に背いた踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you the way to dance that defies truth, goodness, and beauty,
いっせーので狂っちまえ 惨めな姿で
so on three, go crazy in your miserable state.
何十何百何千何万何億人の中でさぁ
Among tens, hundreds, thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of people,
そうして埋もれていたっていいと どうして言えるのだろう
how can you say it's fine to stay buried like that?
ねぇ 世界が患っている狂信は
Hey, the fanaticism the world suffers from
健常者でさえ目が眩むような光を放っている
emits a light that dazzles even the healthy.
今夜 悪魔がお前らにこう言うぜ
Tonight, the devil says to you all:
「神とやらになど惑わされるなよ」
"Don't be deceived by so-called gods."
はーい！
All right!
『悪魔の踊り方』歌わせていただきました！
That was "Devil's Manner"!
いや、『悪魔の踊り方』ってさ、すごいかっこいい曲じゃない？
Man, "Devil's Manner" is such a cool song, isn't it?
ああいうかっこいい歌歌うと、なんかちゃんと様になっているのかなーって
When I sing a cool song like that, I wonder if I pulled it off properly...
なんか心細い気持ちに実際はなっているんだよね。
To be honest, I was actually feeling a bit nervous!
ちゃんとカッコよく歌えてたかな、僕？
Was I able to sing it coolly?
はい！
Alright!
ということでね、なんかもうここまであっという間だったよね！
So anyway, time has really flown by so fast up to this point!
もうこんな時間経ってるんだーっていう感じではございますが、
I can hardly believe it's already this time, but...
なんとですね、
surprisingly...
ま、ここから告知タイムとさせていただきます！
Well, from here on, it's time for announcements!
はい、です、かー！
Hi, everyone!
えー、まずはみんなに見ても頂きたいCMがございます！
First off, we have a commercial that I'd like you all to watch!
あ、やばい！みんな、心して...どうぞ！
Oh my! Everyone, brace yourselves... Here it is!
ここからは檜山修之が猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2026のグッズをご紹介するぞ！まずはこれだ！
From here on, Nobuyuki Hiyama will introduce the Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration 2026 Goods! First, we have this!
はっぴ〜おかゆはっぴ〜
Happi~ Okayu Happi~
神岡ちろる先生の描き下ろしイラストが描かれた法被がグッズになったぞ！
A happi coat featuring a newly drawn illustration by Kamioka Chiroru-sensei is now merch!
きょとん顔のおかゆんがとてもキュート！
Okayu with a bewildered face is super cute!
イベントやライブに着ていけば一目でおにぎりゃーアピールできるスーパーハッピーなグッズだ！
If you wear this to events or live shows, it's a super happy item that lets you show off as an Onigirya at a glance!
お出かけに連れてってアクリルスタンド！
Take Me Out Acrylic Stand!
アクスタはもう家に飾るだけの時代じゃない！日々のお出かけを彩る、推し活マストアイテム！
Acrylic stands aren't just for displaying at home anymore! It's a must-have fan item to brighten up your daily outings!
ポーチに入れて外に持ち運んで、おかゆんに世界を沢山見せてあげてくれよな！
Put it in your pouch, carry it outside, and show Okayun the world!
ごくごく！BIGたんぶら〜
Gulp-Gulp! BIG Tumbler~
甘城なつき先生描き下ろしのミニキャラが描かれた大容量のタンブラー！
A large-capacity tumbler featuring a mini-character drawn by Amagi Natsuki-sensei!
持ち手やストローもついているので、外出時はもちろん、勉強中や仕事中、様々なシチュエーションで大活躍間違いなし！
It comes with a handle and straw, so it's guaranteed to be a huge hit when going out, studying, working, or in any situation!
おかゆんの配信を見る時にも使ってくれ！！
Use it when watching Okayun's streams too!!
おでかけおにぎり型ショルダーポーチ！
Outing Onigiri Shoulder Pouch!
アクスタやhololive friends to Goなどちょっとした小物が入る優れたショルダーポーチだぜ！
An excellent shoulder pouch that can hold small items like acrylic stands or hololive friends to Go!
透明素材なので日々の推し活に使える一品となっているぞ！
Since it's made of transparent material, it's a great item for your daily fan activities!
そして... フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And... here is the full set purchase bonus!
なんとフルセットを購入した全員に猫又おかゆ直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてくる！
Surprisingly, everyone who buys the full set gets a postcard with Nekomata Okayu's hand-written signature & duplicated message!
おにぎりゃーのみんな！絶対ゲットしてくれよな！
All you Onigirya out there! Be sure to get it!
やばーい！
That was amazing!
ということで、あの...檜山修之さんに生誕グッズのCMを撮っていただきました！やばい！
So, um... Nobuyuki Hiyama-san recorded the commercial for my birthday merch! That's insane!
もう檜山修之さんというね、レジェンドの声優さんがいらっしゃいまして、猫又おかゆ、ホロライブデビュー時からの世界で一番大好きな声優さんとなっております！
Nobuyuki Hiyama-san is a legendary voice actor, and ever since my Hololive debut, he's been my absolute favorite voice actor in the entire world!
あの、この場をお借りして、あの、檜山修之さん、本当にありがとうございました！
I'd like to take this opportunity to say... Nobuyuki Hiyama-san, thank you so very much!
興奮冷めやらぬなんですが...
I'm still so excited, but...
あの、CMにあった通り、猫又おかゆ生誕グッズ2026を発売させていただきますので、皆さん是非ご予約お待ちしてます！
As seen in the commercial, Nekomata Okayu Birthday Goods 2026 are now available, so everyone, please make your pre-orders!
そして、告知は一つだけじゃないんですね。
And that's not the only announcement.
続きまして、こちら！ドンドン！
Next up, this! Ta-da!
いよいよお待ちかね！来月3月26日木曜日に「おかゆにゅ〜む！」...
Finally, what you've been waiting for! Next month on Thursday, March 26th, 'Okaunyum! Part 1'
「R」...
...'R'...
「おかゆにゅ〜む！R」がリリース！
...'Okaunyum! R' is releasing!
青森を舞台に君と2人で商品開発という名の恋人旅行がスタート！
Set in Aomori, a romantic trip with you disguised as product development begins!
笑いあり、デートあり、野球拳もあり...
Laughter, dates, and even strip-poker...
盛りだくさんの作品となっております！
It's a feature-packed game!
自分で...自分で「野球拳あり」って何言ってんだと思っちゃったね。
I just thought to myself, 'Why did I say strip-poker included?'
うん、自分で言ったくせにね。僕が野球拳やりたいって言ったくせにね。
Yeah, even though I'm the one who said it. Even though I was the one who said I wanted strip-poker.
そして、野球拳あるのに「CERO審査大丈夫なのかよ」というお声、あの、度々いただいておりますが...
And even with strip-poker, we've often received comments asking, 'Will it pass CERO rating?'...
なんと、心配していたCERO審査も無事に「C」で決まりました！
And believe it or not, the CERO rating we were worried about safely came out as 'C'!
ふぅー、良かった良かった！
Phew, what a relief!
うん！そしてみんな体験版ももう既に遊んでくれたかな？
Yep! And has everyone played the demo version already?
あのドキドキの続きは是非君の目で確かめてほしいな！
I hope you'll check out what happens after that heart-throbbing part with your own eyes!
まだまだたくさんの未公開情報もあるとのことなので、「おかゆにゅ〜む！R」から目が離せないよ！
There's still plenty of unrevealed info coming, so keep your eyes glued to 'Okaunyum! R'!
是非お楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
そして、こちら最後の告知となります！
And here is the final announcement!
毎年発表させていただいているんですが、今日もライブの最後に...
We announce this every year, but today, at the end of the live stream...
新曲を発表させていただきます！
I'll be announcing a new song!
はぁ〜、やっと言えた！
Phew, I finally got to say it!
今回はですね、てにをはさんに作詞作曲をしていただきました！ありがとうございます、てにをはさん！
This time, Ten'iwoha-san wrote the lyrics and composed the music for me! Thank you so much, Ten'iwoha-san!
ではでは
Well then, well then,
あの、色々言いたいこととかもあるんですが、
well, there are various things I'd like to say, but...
まずは君の目で しっかりと聴いていただければなと
first, I hope you listen closely with your own eyes...
見ていただければなと思っております
and watch it closely.
ではでは
Well then,
聴いてください
please listen.
ノンデリシャス
Non-delicious.
今日もカム カム 1 2 3
Chewing today too, chew, 1 2 3
舌も踊るよ 1 2 3
My tongue dances too, 1 2 3
トラウマをじっくり煮込んだボルシチ どうぞ
Borscht carefully simmered with trauma, here you go
キミの心臓は歯型だらけさ
Your heart is covered in bite marks
苦肉のステーキとセルフィッシュ＆チップス
Desperate steak and selfish & chips
マンネリを刻んだサラダ
A salad chopped with rut
こんなにもおいしい食卓
Such a delicious dinner table
邪魔しないで
Don't get in the way
お口を開けてはいあーん
Open your mouth and say ahh
ウェイター ウェイター お皿を下げないで
Waiter, waiter, don't clear the plates
これがボクの“おいしい”ものなんだから
Because this is my "delicious" stuff
ハングリー ロンリー グラトニー
Hungry, lonely, gluttony
新しいメニュー
A new menu
みんな クワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, you've been eagerly waiting
デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
De-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテーブル蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away such a table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Everyday, every night, don't gorge yourself
ノンデリシャス なんべんだっておかわり
Non-delicious, seconds no matter how many times
おえ
Ugh
お皿積み上げ 3 4 5
Stacking up plates, 3 4 5
バベルみたいに 3 4 5
Like Babel, 3 4 5
喉の奥につっかえて窒息しかけても
Even if it gets stuck in the throat and almost suffocates me
大人は飲み込むらしい すっごいね
Adults seem to swallow it down, incredible, isn't it?
義理人情サンドイッチ 情熱の冷めたスープ
Duty and humanity sandwich, cold soup of passion
そんなもの頼んでないから
I didn't order anything like that
ボクはボクで好きなものだけ食べるだけ
I'll just eat what I like as myself
飢え 際限なくもう出てきて
Starvation, boundless, now come out
これがボクの“おいしい”日々なんだから
Because these are my "delicious" days
異論 反論 諸々 飲み込んだあとで
After swallowing objections, counterarguments, and all kinds of things
挑め ダイエット ダイエット
Challenge yourself, diet, diet
一心不乱に噛む カム
Chewing whole-heartedly, chew
不条理を噛む
Chewing absurdity
のらりくらり 幸せそうな顔して
Sluggishly, with a happy face
噛む カム 悪魔で噛む
Chew, chew, chew like a devil
みんな クワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, you've been eagerly waiting
デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
De-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテーブル蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away such a table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Everyday, every night, don't gorge yourself
ノンデリシャス でもなんべんだっておかわりしよう
Non-delicious, but let's have seconds no matter how many times
おにぎりぁ〜！！ 今日は祝ってくれて ほんとにありがとう！
[Message] To Onigiri! Thank you so much for celebrating today!
毎日がハッピーなのも皆のおかげ♡ ず〜っと一緒にいようね ちょっとでも皆の笑顔のきっかけになれますように... 猫又おかゆ
Every happy day is thanks to you ♡ Let's stay together forever! I hope to bring a smile to your face... — Nekomata Okayu